# Neil Wilcoxson

### Summary

Motivated Computer Science student with internship and academic experience in software development and systems engineering. Interested in full time opportunities starting January 2020.

Software Development, Data Analysis, Project Planning, System Testing Languages and Tools: C, C++, Java, JUnit, Maven, Python, Bash, SQL, Git, Linux

### Education

### Baylor University | Waco, TX | BS in Computer Science (graduation Dec. 2019)

- GPA: 3.7 (Major) | 3.5 (Overall)
- Relevant Coursework
  - Intro to CS (C++)
  - Discrete Structures
  - Data Structures Algorithms
- Java Programming
- Systems Programing (C)
- Computer Systems (x86 Assembly Programming)
- Computer Architecture
- Operating Systems
- Software Engineering
- Database Design
- Networking
- Competitive Cybersecurity
- **Business Communications**

## **Employment History**

Software Engineer Intern | Viasat | Carlsbad, CA | May 2018 - August 2018 Developed an approach to demonstrate a satellite acceleration product for Global Business Solutions (GBS) including performance measurement and analysis

- Authored and implemented a project plan
- Configured hardware systems for prototype demos (Modems, Routers, VPN, etc.)
- Developed software for demonstration, test, and analysis (Java, JavaFX)
- Logged, analyzed, and presented system performance data

Broadcast Video Producer | North Coast Church | Vista, CA | 2013 - 2017 Produced live and recorded video programming for large multi-site church

- Configured satellite equipment for live broadcast (5 off-site venues, 10,000+ viewers)
- Transcoded video files for distribution (H.264, ProRes)
- Installed, configured, and tested broadcast equipment (AJA, Blackmagic, etc.)

### Student **Organizations**

### **C4C (Computing for Compassion)** | Secretary (2017 - Present)

- Developed software to support charitable activities for local non-profits
- Hosted community outreach events to promote interest in technology
- Coordinated volunteers and resources for annual hackathon

Upsilon Pi Epsilon (UPE) International Computer Science Honor Society

**Baylor ACM (Association for Computing Machinery)** 

**Baylor Driving Club** 

• Various automotive events (Autocross, Rallye, Cars and Coffee)

#### Achievements

### President's Gold Scholarship | Baylor University

### Eagle Scout Rank | Boy Scouts of America

- Designed and led community service project totaling 150 volunteer hours
- Led Scouts as Senior Patrol Leader (2+ years), Webmaster (3+ years)